Hi again! As promised, we're going to
discuss user testing and feedback.
If the end goal of our project is to have
a great quality product or service for
both our own organization and
our customer,
we need to get an idea of
what the customer wants.
We already learned how to make sure
something is high quality on our end.
Now let's find out how to measure what
clients want, so we can meet their needs,
expectations, and standards.
The best way to get an idea of what
customers and users want is to ask them,
but we don't mean calling each
of them up on the phone and
literally asking them. That might
not be the best use of our time.
Fortunately, there are a few ways
we can streamline that information.
We can conduct a series of surveys or
tests with customers and users.
Some common ones are feedback surveys and
user acceptance tests.
Let's start with feedback surveys.
Feedback surveys are a survey in which
users provide feedback on features of
your product that they like or dislike.
These surveys can take
place as you design,
before you launch, in order to find out if
people like and understand the product,
or after you've launched, if you want to
make sure the user experience is even
more satisfying.
So your users participate in a survey and
give you feedback on what
features they like or dislike,
and potentially, which aspects
they find to be fairly intuitive,
and which aspects are a little
tougher to navigate.
After you get that feedback, you'll either
be good to launch, if you haven't yet,
or you'll go back and iterate on
the product, if it's already on the market.
Alternatively, you might
conduct user acceptance tests.
In broader terms, a user acceptance test,
or a UAT, is a test that helps
a business make sure that a product or
solution works for its users.
A UAT must meet the agreed
upon requirements and
deliver the expected results.
This test is typically used to
assess the end-to-end experience for
the user of a new process or product.
A user acceptance test is incredibly
important because it takes place near
the end of a product's development,
and therefore, is an overall user
experience test of the entire product,
software, or service.
UATs are sometimes
referred to as "beta tests."
Let's find out what a user acceptance
test agenda might look like.
In a typical UAT setting,
you'll welcome your users and
thank them for participating.
Then, you'll present the product to them.
This includes discussing
testing guidelines and
demonstrating how the product works.
Next, you'll start your UAT test cases,
taking your audience through
critical user journeys.
A critical user journey is a sequence
of steps a user follows to accomplish
tasks in your product.
When presenting something you've built,
you must give users a visual
representation or mock up of your
product or have them go through a demo.
For example, if you're working on
a construction-based project and
you intend to replace all appliances and
hardware in the home,
you'll want to give the user some sort
of vision of what that might entail.
This could include 3D models,
digital blueprints, samples, and more.
Your UAT demo should focus
on a call to action.
For instance, the call to action for
your project may be the need to test
hardware in the client's future home.
Maybe the homeowners have requested a
dishwasher that can be opened and
closed with very little force and
doesn't make too much noise.
In that case,
you'll want to give the client real-life scenarios to work within.
Ask them to load the dishes and
start the wash cycle.
Then ask questions like, "On a scale of
one to 10, how much force was required to
open and close the dishwasher?" to determine if the washer meets their expectations.
During your presentation and
walkthrough of the UAT,
you should be collecting feedback from
the users on their overall experience.
During this part of testing,
your users will be able to help you
identify edge cases. Edge cases
are rare—outliers that the original
requirements didn't account for.
They deal with the extreme maximums and
minimums of parameters.
For example, imagine that you
created an app that allows for
unlimited photo uploads,
knowing that users will rarely upload more
than 1000 photos in a single session.
How will the system deal with someone
who actually does upload thousands of
photos, or millions, in a single upload?
It's unlikely, but
it could be disastrous for your software.
After identifying edge cases, the last
step of the UAT agenda is to recap
your findings, identify bugs or issues, and
prioritize which issues
need to be addressed first.
When you've addressed the issue and
determined next steps,
you'll be able close and
conclude your user acceptance testing.
And there you have it!
So we've learned a bit more about the
importance of listening to feedback from
customers
and discussed some common methods for
measuring customer satisfaction, like
feedback surveys,
user acceptance tests, and edge cases.
That's a lot to learn.
Keep it up!
You're doing great so far!
In our next video, we'll pivot to
identifying reasons why risks and
changes might occur and
how to manage dependencies.
I'll see you soon.